So, in the previous videos,
在前面的视频中
we have already done some things to work with
我们做了一些处理缺失值的练习
missing values in terms of dropping or imputing.
使用删除或填充的方式
When we impute it, we were able to fit models to predict all of the salaries.
如果选择填充缺失值 我们可以对所有样本作出预测
However, we still weren't making use of all of these categorical columns.
但是 我们仍然没有充分利用分类变量
And so, in this video,
所以 在这个视频中
we're gonna go through how we can make use of those categorical columns,
我们会了解如何利用分类变量
and one of the main ways is through zero, one encodings.
主要方法就是使用 0/1 编码 (也称独热编码)
There are few different advantages to this approach which is why it's pretty popular,
这种方法具备一些优势 使其比较受欢迎
but there are scalability issues which you'll
但它也存在可扩展性的问题
see in some of the runtimes of things in this notebook that make
你会在本次 Notebook 某些代码运行的时候看到
it sort of a disadvantage when you have a lot of variables like in this dataset
当有很多分类变量的时候 比如当前数据集
we have a lot of categorical variables and that can lead to scaling issues.
就会导致可扩展性的问题 这也是独热编码的劣势
So you'll see that throughout this notebook,
在这个 Notebook 中就可以看到
and there are potentially other ways that could work around those scaling issues.
对于可扩展性问题 其实有其他的应对办法
So, in the first part of the notebook,
在 Notebook 的第一部分
we're basically just doing the things that
我们只是在重复
you've already seen in some of the other screencast.
之前视频里走过的步骤
So we read in the data set,
读取数据
we look at the numeric variables,
选择数值型变量
we drop any of the rows that are missing the salary,
删除 Salary 存在缺失值的数据
we fill in the mean for each column that has a missing value,
用均值填充其他列的缺失数据
We split into X and y.
将数据划分为 X 和 y
We split it into training and test.
拆分训练集和测试集
And then, we see how well our model performs on the test data,
然后评估模型的表现
and you can see that result here.
在这里可以看到结果
And then, using the rest of this notebook,
在 Notebook 剩下的内容中
we're going to see if we can't build a model that does better than
我们主要是想看看 使用分类变量
this by using all of the categorical variables.
会不会提升模型的表现
So, this first part says,
第一个问题
use df to identify the columns that are categorical in nature,
找出 df 数据中的分类变量
and basically subset to a dataframe only holding the categorical variables.
提取出只包含分类变量的数据部分
And then, they give us this useful link which I have opened up here.
这里还给了一个文档链接 打开看一下
And there's this really nice part within it,
打开的页面中 这里的内容比较有用
you can select the data types of any dataframe using this select dtypes,
你可以使用 select_dtypes 来筛选出特定数据类型的列
and then, basically, you pass in.
基本上只需要传入类型名称
You could pass an int, float, object, boolean,
比如 int float object bool 等
any of the data types that you might see,
所有你可以看到的数据类型
you could pass into this include part,
都可以传入到 include 参数中
and then that'll subset the data frame to only include those.
该函数就会返回数据子集 其中只包含指定数据类型的列
Great. So, select dtypes and include equals,
好的 使用 select_dtypes 设定 include 参数
and then we pass it a list and we just want to include object.
传入的是一个列表 我们只需要 object 类型
We're just going to store it in a new part.
然后将结果存在 cat_df 里面
And it says, there are 147 columns that are associated with that,
这里显示 有 147 列是分类变量
and if we wanted to look at this.
打印数据看一下
And we can see that all of these columns look like they're
可以看到这些列都是分类变量
categorical in nature whereas if we look at their original dataframe,
如果再来看原数据集
we have this respondent part that got dropped from here.
可以看到 respondent 在 cat_df 中被删除了
Yeah. We have the salary and expected salary down here at the end that also got dropped.
后面的工资和预期工资两列也被删除了
And then, we can check that against the solution.
检查答案
Says, "Nice job, it looks like you did that right."
回答正确
Cool. And so then it says.
接下来的问题是
"Use the cat_df and the cells below to fill in
使用 cat_df 回答 cat_df_dict 字典中的问题
the dictionary with the correct value for each statement."
在字典对应位置 填写正确的数字
So the first statement is,
第一个问题是
"What are the number of columns with missing values?"
不存在缺失值的列数是多少?
So, use cat_df, and we want to
使用 cat_df 我们想要了解的是
So, is null, and if we run this,
先使用 isnull()
basically, that's a bunch of trues and falses.
会得到很多 True 和 False
And if we run a sum,
对这些值进行求和
if we run np.sum on this,
也就是使用 np.sum
we get zeros or some number.
得到了一些 0 值和其他数字
So, this is the number of missing values for each of these columns,
这个结果其实就是每一列包含的缺失值数量
and you can see some of them are zeros.
可以看到有一些列的值是 0
And so, if we pull those, this wave,
我们可以用这种方式提取所有等于 0 的列
we get trues and falses,
又得到了一些 True 和 False
and so we can take another sum.
再次使用 sum
Looks like there's this, cool.
这就是最终结果了
And so then, the next part says,
接下来的问题
the number of columns with more than half of the column missing.
缺失值占比一半以上的列数
And so, we're going to use something very similar to what we did here.
使用跟之前非常相似的方法
But remember, this was a count, and basically,
不过需要注意 这里的是计数
if we want to get a proportion,
如果想要比例的话
we can take the number of rows.
需要将其除以数据行数
So, we can get the number of rows by pulling the first element out of the shape.
数据行数可以由 shape 的第一个元素得到
So, then that will give us the rows.
这个就是数据行数了
And so, if we take this total number of
如果让缺失值数量除以数据总量
that'll give us the proportion of missing values.
就能得到缺失值的比例
So this is the proportion of missing values in each part.
这里就是每个特征包含的缺失值比例
And then, essentially by looking at if that's greater than 0.5 is the first one.
然后 我们可以判断其是否大于 0.5
This should give us trues and falses.
会得到一些 True 和 False
by taking the sum of those, we get 49.
再次取 sum 得到结果是 49
So, 49 appear to have more than half of the column missing.
也就是说 有 49 列的缺失值比例是大于 50% 的
And then, the last one is 75 percent.
最后一个是 超过 75% 缺失值的列数
And so, that's a quick change of this,
这个很好办 就是修改下数字
and it looks like there are 13.
结果是 13
And we could do that with any percentage so we could say,
其实可以用任何的值来比较
are there 80 percent of them missing,
比如说 80%
or is there 90?
或者是 90%
Only five percent.
或者 5%
So then, in this last part,
在最后的部分
we're working with this dummy var dataframe,
我们使用 dummy_var_df 数据集
and you can see that there are two columns,
其中有两列
and one has these a and b values,
有一列只有 a 和 b 两种值
and one has numeric.
另一个是数值型的
And I use the cell to basically dummy col1.
我用这个单元格 为 col1 创建虚拟变量
So, we are interested in creating dummy variables
我们想做的是为所有的分类变量创建虚拟变量
and so, that would be col1, but this numeric variable, we don't want a dummy in that.
在这里 就是 col1 列 而对于这个数值型变量 则不需要虚拟编码
In most cases, we could create a dummy variable that just says is that missing or not.
很多时候 我们可以为其创建虚拟变量 只用来识别是否缺失
We might be able to come up with another way to actually be able to use these numbers
也许以后可以想出另一种方法来实际使用这些数字
as well as information about if there's missing values.
以及是否含有缺失值的信息
So, the first question is just,
第一个问题是
which column should we create a dummy variable for?
我们需要对哪一列创建虚拟变量?
And that would be col1. So, that's b.
应该是 col1 也就是 d
When you use the default settings for creating dummy variables,
如果使用默认设置创建虚拟变量
how many are created?
会创建多少列?
So when you use the default settings for creating dummy variables, how many are created?
如果使用创建默认设置创建虚拟变量 会创建多少列?
So, yeah, if we run this,
如果运行这行代码
so this get dummies will create dummy variables for us,
该函数会为我们创建虚拟变量
and we pass it a column,
我们传入一个列
and it'll create the dummy variables for that column,
它会为这个列创建虚拟变量
it'll create the one, zero encodings.
使用 0 或 1 进行编码
And in this case, it created two columns by default.
在这个示例中 创建了 2 列
And then, it says, what happens with the Nan values.
下一个问题 缺失值是如何处理的?
So, if we look back at this, basically,
回到这里
there were NaN values for the index of five and the index of seven,
索引 5 和 7 的地方其实是有缺失值的
and if we look at those,
看一下这两行数据
basically, they were just always given as zero.
它们的值都是 0
So they weren't dropped that then become these numbers or anything like that,
该函数不会删除缺失值
they were just always encoded with a zero.
而是将缺失值编码为 0
All right. So then, it says,
好的 下一个问题
notice use get_dummies to encode NaNs.
注意 get_dummies 可以对 NaN 值进行编码
There's also this dummy_na argument.
其中有一个 dummy_na 参数
And so, you can use this dummy_na argument which is essentially just a boolean.
你可以使用 dummy_na 参数 传入一个布尔值
So if you look at this,
我们来看一下官方文档
the dummy na is just a boolean,
dummy_na 参数是布尔值
and it's by default, a false.
默认值是 False
And when it's false,
当设置为 False 时
then the NaNs are ignored,
就会忽略 NaN 值
meaning they just become zeros.
也就是将其编码为 0
But if you add a true,
如果设置为 True
then a new column is added that will indicate the NaNs.
就会增加一列虚拟变量 标识是否缺失数据
So, let's see if we can use this.
我们来看一下能不能用
We want to pass the first column to this column one.
传入第一列数据 col1
We're gonna pass the first column,
传入了第一列
and we want dummy_na to be true, right?
然后把 dummy_na 设为 True
So this says, do something with those NAs so that I know that they exist.
这句代码的作用是 将缺失值表示出来
And now you can see that we have this new column that's responsible for the NaNs,
于是 这里就能看到一个新列 nan
and there's a one over here,
这里有一个 1
whereas before we just had these two zeros.
而之前 只是在这两个地方看到两个 0
And we can check that against the solution.
我们可以检查下答案
Cool. So, then in this last part,
回答正确! 在最后一部分
what we're interested in doing is creating
我们想做的是
a new dataframe that essentially takes care of all of these categorical columns.
创建一个处理了所有分类变量的数据集
So, essentially we want to do
也就是说
this process for all of the categorical variables in our dataframe and then
我们要将这个流程应用于数据集的每个分类变量
create a new dataframe that has these characteristics that
然后创建一个新的数据集
has these dummy variables for each of our categorical variables.
其中包含所有分类变量的虚拟变量
So, it says, the new dataframe should
题目要求 新的数据集应该包含所有列 不仅仅是分类特征
So that means if they were floats, or ints,
也就是说 如果数据类型为 float、int
or anything like that, we still want to have those columns in our dataframe.
或其他任何类型 都应该包含在我们的数据集中
It removes all the original columns
其中移除了所有原始的数据列
so we don't need any of the categorical columns once we dummy variable them.
也就是说 有了虚拟变量 就不再需要原来的分类变量了
And then, the dummy columns for each categorical variable should be in this dataframe,
然后 每个分类变量的虚拟变量都应该包含在该数据集中
and then, if this is specified as true it should also contain that extra column.
如果 dummy_na 设为 True 还需要包含额外的列
So you can see, we just want to pass it the data frame,
可以看到 这里的参数是 df
the columns that are categorical and whether or not we wanted dummy them.
分类类型的列 以及是否要处理缺失值
Here's what a pretty complex one line solution looks like.
这里有一行非常复杂的代码 看似可以完成任务
Essentially, we are using the concat to concatenate
其中实际上就是使用了 concat 函数
both the columns that are categorical as well as the non categorical columns together.
把分类变量和非分类变量拼接到一起
And so, actually, we need to do this for col in cat_cols.
这里还应该要加一个 for col in cat_cols
So, for each column that's categorical,
对于 cat_cols 中的每一列
go in, drop that original column, and then,
进入循环 删除原始列
so this drop axis equals one just says drop the column,
drop 设置 axis=1 也就是删除列
dummy variable that column,
对这一列创建虚拟变量
and then this whole part is basically
这一部分
just what we want that dummy variable column to look like.
就是虚拟变量的具体设定
So drop the column,
删除第一列
the dummy na part is either a true
dummy_na 这个变量可以指定为 True 或者 False
or false that actually gets passed in, appear at the top.
是这个函数的输入值
And then, I'm also giving a prefix which you could choose to do or not do.
然后我还设置了 prefix_sep 不过你也可以不设置
Yeah. And then a separator for the prefix and that we want to,
该参数是设置列名前缀的分隔符
so this axis equals one part is just going back to the concat argument.
后面的 axis 等于 1 其实是属于 concat 函数
So, for each categorical column,
再理解一次 对每一个分类变量
go in and drop the column,
进入循环 删掉这一列
create the dummy variable for it,
为其创建虚拟变量
and then concatenate that back onto the dataframe with the dropped dummy variable.
最后再把虚拟变量和之前的数据集拼在一起
So, and then return that as
将其保存在 df 中
this dataframe thing and do that for every single categorical column.
再继续循环
So now, we can use this to create our new dataframe using
现在 我们可以用这个函数 为分类变量创建新的 DataFrame 了
the categorical columns and make sure that it checks against the shape that you'd expect.
确保再检查一下 shape 符合预期
And then, there's this big long function.
接下来 是一个很长的函数
But the good part is,
不过好消息是
most of what you're doing is what happened up here.
你需要做的大部分其实主要是前面做过的内容
So, you're basically just using what you've already
基本上用之前完成的部分
done up here to finish that last part out.
就能完成最后的任务了